# ERIK HASSE, Ph.D.

erik.g.hasse@gmail.com 507 · 995 · 3159

#### **SUMMARY**

Machine Learning Engineer passionate about deploying scientific computing into the real world. Experienced in Python and Scala with a focus on time series forecasting and optimization. Excited about sharing knowledge and helping the team succeed.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages Python (8 years), SQL (5 years), Scala (1 year)

Python packages Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-Learn, Plotly, Matplotlib, Pydantic, FastAPI,

Streamlit, Django ORM, SQLAlchemy, Pytest, Scalene

Scala packages Akka, Akka-HTTP, Tapir, Circe, gRPC, Scalatest

Tools Bash, Git, Docker, Jenkins, Github Actions, Jira, MLFlow,

Cloud providers (AWS, GCP, Azure)

## RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

#### Fermata Energy

Vehicle-to-everything platform provider

Staff Machine Learning Engineer

August 2022-Present

- · Design and implement a package for simulating bidirectional electric vehicle chargers in Python to support market research, model development, and site optimization
- · Integrate backend services with third-party APIs to receive signals from utilities and market operators
- · Develop an orchestration service in Scala to conditionally run optimization models
- · Deploy models and optimization services into a production environment using REST APIs, gRPC services, and Argo Workflows
- · Support team members through code reviews, pair programming, and sharing best practices

## Lowe's Home Improvement

Nationwide retailer

Lead Machine Learning Engineer

December 2019-July 2022

- · Developed a platform for data scientists to track, store, and deploy their models as an API
- · Implemented time series models predicting sales of thousands of items across 1700 stores to optimize workforce scheduling, improving margins by over \$10 million per year
- · Created a platform for automating forecasting and time series anomaly detection and provided other data scientists with tools to build models on this platform

Freddie Mac

Mortgage backer and insurer

Senior Data Scientist

October 2018-December 2019

University of Iowa

Mathematics Teaching Assistant

August 2013-May 2018

## **EDUCATION**

### University of Iowa

Ph.D. in Mathematics
M.S. in Mathematics
May 2013

# North Dakota State University

B.S. in Mathematics, Minor in Computer Science

May 2013